<!-- 비평 3. 이슬비 평론 (영문 버전) -->
        <div id="critique-3" class="content-group">
            <div class="section-title"><mark>Critique</mark></div>
            <br>
            <div class="caption">
                <span style="font-weight: bold; font-size: 16px; color: #000 !important;">
                    Dead Stock or Vintage
                </span><br>
                <span>Seulbi Lee (Independent Curator / Director of Philosopher's Store)</span><br>
                <span style="font-size: 12px; color: #666;">Clayarch Gimhae Museum Ceramic Creative Center 2023 Resident Artist Critique</span><br><br>
                
                <a href="files/Critique_LeeSeulbi_EN.pdf" download style="font-weight: bold; text-decoration: underline; color: #000 !important;">
                    [Download PDF] Original PDF
                </a>
            </div>
            <br><hr style="border: 0; border-top: 1px solid #eee;"><br>
            
            <!-- 평론 영문 본문 (한글 단락과 1:1 매칭) -->
            <div style="line-height: 1.8; color: #222; font-size: 14px; text-align: justify; word-break: keep-all;">
                <!-- 단락 1 -->
                <p>
                    Where some people see certain things as simply junk that’s been thrown away, there are others who see items that can be resold and in that way gain value. This is the case for most stuff found at flea markets. Some may see those things as only useless trash, but to others who know their value, no place could be more fascinating. Rummaging through piles of old vintage items is like a treasure hunt. If you go to a flea market or vintage goods shop in Europe, you might get really lucky and come upon something rare and unexpected. On top of that, many of the things found in such vintage markets are inspiring in themselves, perhaps because of the sort of energy that is concentrated within old objects.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 2 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    Is the idea that objects possess spirits or souls just a spooky myth that thrilled us as children? I would argue it is not. Just because this unfathomable, obscure energy cannot be proven scientifically doesn’t mean we can simply shrug it off, when the sense that it exists is so clearly undeniable. The uncanny feeling this gives us also confers a sense of déjà vu. Again, where some see an object that has outlived its usefulness and no longer has any value, others see a precious object filled with cherished memories. As such, value can be defined through many different measures, from a variety of perspectives, since items’ personal and social value is determined through diverse criteria.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 3 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    For such objects to find a new use in the language of art is already a familiar trope. It is well known in the sphere of art that the “found object” (Objet Trouvé) has transformed the artist’s role in the act of production. Another implication is that the artistic techniques for representation have been replaced by acts of the intellect. When Marcel Duchamp showed his work “Fountain,” he set in motion the presentation of existing prefabricated objects as works of art, widely used by Dadaists and Surrealists under the moniker of “readymades.” The act of “selecting” an industrial product, or some existing object that has already been made, was transposed into an act of artistic creation.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 4 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    And now, today, in an age when most ready-made prefabricated products are easily produced, easily used, and easily discarded, what about the image? In the present day where there is a glut of virtually everything, images are likewise no exception. For artists, whose main material is the image, the abundance of both online and offline images become effective materials and motifs. Think of selecting an image that has already been created, or choosing certain “ones” from among a flood of images and objects. Even if the artist isn’t aware of it, borrowing images in this way, even for partial use, is tantamount to a modern take on the methodology of using readymades and found objects. Kixung Eum is no exception.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 5 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    The three-dimensional sculptures produced by Eum are collages made up of “found images” collected by the artist. Fragmented images are overlapped and juxtaposed together to create something enigmatic, and then resin is poured over it to refine the form. The hardened resin gives the individual sheets of paper the physicality of a three-dimensional object. The sources consist of advertisements from old magazines bought in secondhand shops, random flyers and leaflets found around the city, and pictures from old photo albums with no connection to the artist. All of them represent a certain time, or the life of some individual, but like a wandering spirit, no one can say where they’re from. Taking a close look at the artist’s series “The Scrapbook” (2023), you’ll find magazine ads featuring models wearing clothes that were once fashionable, pictures of military items that could be from anywhere, jumbled-up newspaper articles in Korean, Japanese, English, and French, and mixed in with all this, illegal advertising cards and flyers like you might have seen lying around in a public restroom the other day. In the sense that the word ‘scrapbook’ refers to a collection of purposefully selected and organized items, these three-dimensional sculptures composed of haphazard combinations of mixed images belie the series title, conversely seeming to represent the jumbled-up nature of contemporary society.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 6 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    Walking around unfamiliar neighborhoods and alleys, the artist collected all sorts of completely different everyday images he came across in different areas and locations. Afterwards, he edited and reworked his choices. Eum said that the fleeting experiences that happen to him when he’s in a completely different place can sometimes feel unreal. That sensation of déjà vu also occurs when you see certain objects. For example, an abandoned doll or toy, or discarded household item, reminds you of a familiar and commonplace time, while at the same time feeling strange and unfamiliar. That “uncanny” feeling of finding something both familiar and strange at the same time is a sensation that happens to us more often than we might think.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 7 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    In this way, the resulting amassments of fragmented images are deployed as a single piece. So it is with “Unknown” (2022) and “The Time Keeper” (2021–2022), as well. In “The Time Keeper,” the artist has put together various objects he collected and then poured resin over them, seemingly preserving time intact, as its title suggests. Things like cassette tapes, toys, and somebody’s house keys are all part of a convoluted tangle of ownerless stuff that feels old and worn-out, but is conversely also suggestive of some pop-culture phenomenon, giving off a retro vibe. Creating combinations of images or objects that started off with the act of fanatical collecting is the definition of kitsch itself. The artist breaks his found objects and images into pieces and puts them back together again to create new objects. However, these new objects have no purpose or utility. What verges even more on kitsch is the artist’s desire to display these objects as things in themselves. Kitsch has become an established pop culture phenomenon for the reason that the definition of “high art,” its ostensible opposite, has become ambiguous. But it is also because the sort of lowbrow art and B-level content represented by kitsch contain their own distinct characteristics and aesthetic features.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 8 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    Just as trends come and go and everything old becomes new again, with vintage and retro looks in vogue, Eum’s works containing overlapping traces of many different time periods preserve the sense of déjà vu in old objects intact. The mania for retro objects that kindle nostalgia is driven not by a wish to go back to earlier times, but rather by a desire to fondly recall and reminisce about the past. The past itself reverts to memory, so objects embodying a given time period will be valued differently, depending on the individual. And as for Eum’s sculptures, constructed on this basis—how will they be interpreted? What’s left after retro? Reminiscing about the past does not necessarily mean wanting to go back to those days. The retro phenomenon may just be empty repetitions of earlier fads, but that does not mean it is meaningless. More than anything, it reveals the character of the times of the public consuming it.
                </p>
                <!-- 단락 9 -->
                <p style="margin-top: 15px;">
                    Just as some old wines simply go bad while others come with a vintage label, the value of an object also depends on the accumulation of time. Eum’s objects: marked transparent threads intertwining traces of many nationalities, various time periods, and any number of individuals. His personal tastes are on full display in a mix of elements, including but not limited to religious icons, the head of Venus, and graffiti-like scrawls in apparent imitation of Basquiat. Meanwhile, in one corner of the artist’s studio are large boxes and shelves filled with photos he has collected, dusty old books, antiques or pieces of junk, household trash, and vintage items. This is the stockpile from which Eum sources his materials. When it comes to evaluating his bizarre hybrid objects, as the famous Internet meme asks, are they “dead stock or vintage”? It all depends on whoever recognizes their value, like being able to spot treasure among heaps of old stuff.
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>